A Finding Aid to the Solon H. Borglum and Borglum Family Papers, 1864-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.borgsolo
Archives of American Art
- Solon Borglum Biography, 1870-1975, undated; Series 5; (Box 3-8; 5.3 linear feet; Not Scanned)
  This series contains materials compiled or written by Monica Borglum Davies and her husband A. Mervyn Davies for the biography, Solon H. Borglum "A Man Who Stands Alone" (Pequot Press, 1974). Found here are numerous files of information gathered during the research process, including photocopies of materials such as correspondence, and documents from Solon's time in the military. Users should note that some of the photocopies of correspondence may overlap with material found in Family and General Correspondence (Series 2 and 3), however, many letters in this series include transcripts. Research files and notes also include lists of photographs, artwork, and students, as well as numerous loose notes, note cards and notebooks created in the process of writing the book. Also found in this series are other writings by Monica and A. Mervyn Davies giving background information and a synopsis of the biography project.
  The bulk of this series consists of heavily edited drafts of the biography. One subseries contains drafts of each section of the book. Researchers should note that many draft chapters do not correspond to or have different titles from the chapters in the published version. Another subseries includes draft manuscripts. All of the manuscripts are for the Borglum biography, but the authors were using various titles, including "A Clear Spirit," and "A Quiet Victory." Many drafts are incomplete and untitled, and the end of the series contains numbered loose pages from drafts and miscellaneous draft edits and notes, all arranged in their original order. Also found are two edited book proofs.
  None of the documents in this series have been digitized.
  The Solon Borglum Biography series is arranged into 4 subseries:
  5.1: Research Files and Notes, 1870-1975, undated
  5.2: Other Writings, undated
  5.3: Book Section Drafts, 1972-1973, undated
  5.4: Draft Manuscripts, 1970-1974, undated
  - Research Files and Notes, 1870-1975; 5.1
    - Descriptions of Works of Art, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Lists of Students and Acquaintences, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Lists of Photographs of Artwork, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Lists of Works of Art, 1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Note Cards, undated; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 36-38)
    - Research Notes, undated; (9 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-47)
    - Research Notebooks, circa 1972, undated; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
    - Family Correspondence, Photocopies and Transcripts, 1870-1909; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 50-51)
    - Family Correspondence, Photocopies and Transcripts, 1916-1962, undated; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - General Correspondence, Photocopies and Transcripts, 1907-1954; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - American Expeditionary Forces Documents, Photocopies, 1918-1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Documents from the Library of Congress, Photocopies, 1903-1965, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, Photocopies, 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Microfilm, The Hegsted Family, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Microfilm, Incomplete Collection of Newspaper Clippings, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Other Writings, undated; 5.2
    - "The Story of Project", undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "The Two Sculptors Gutzon and Solon Borglum: A Continuing Confusion", undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Synopsis of Biography, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Book Section Drafts, 1972-1973, undated; 5.3
    - Title Page, 1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Table of Contents, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - List of Illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Author's Note, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Preface, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Forward, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Introduction, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
    - Acknowledgements, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - Chapter I, 1972, undated; (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 26-32)
    - Chapter II, undated; (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
    - Chapter III, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
    - Chapter IV, undated; (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Chapter V, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Chapter VI, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
    - Chapter VII, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
    - Chapter VIII, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
    - Chapter IX, 1972, undated; (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 16-22)
    - Chapter X, undated; (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-27)
    - Chapter XI, undated; (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 28-31)
    - Chapter XII, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 32-34)
    - Chapter XIII, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 35-37)
    - Chapter XIV, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
    - Chapter XV, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Chapter XVI, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chapter XVII, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chapter XVIII, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chapter XIX, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Chapter XX, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Epilogue, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chronology, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - References and Bibliography, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Index, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Gutzon Borglum Chapter, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Draft Manuscripts, 1970-1974, undated; 5.4
    - "Art Upon a Larger Scale", undated; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
    - "Art Upon a Larger Scale" Second Version, 1972; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
    - "Borglum the Sculptor", undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
    - "The Borglum Story", Incomplete, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "A Clear Spirit", Incomplete, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
    - "A Quiet Victory", Synopsis and Select Chapters, circa 1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "A Quiet Victory", 1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Solon H. Borglum: A Man Who Stands Alone", 1973; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 25-28)
    - "Solon Hannibal Borglum", undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - "The Story of Two Brothers", Incomplete, undated; (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Untitled Draft, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Untitle and Incomplete Drafts, 1970-1971, undated; (8 folders) (Box 7, Folder 7-14)
    - Numbered Loose Pages from Drafts, undated; (14 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-28)
    - Miscellaneous Draft Edits and Notes, 1974, undated; (21 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-21)
    - Book Proof, circa 1973 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Book Proof, Second Copy, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Financial and Business Records, 1898-1998, undated; Series 6; (Box 8, 13; 0.2 linear feet)
  Financial and business records contain materials documenting Solon Borglum's professional work and legacy. Financial materials include bank account books, receipts and statements, ledgers, and price lists, as well as the financial notes and ledger for the Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund. Also found is a financial proposal for the 1905 Lewis and Clark Centennial, and an account book for the posthumous production and sales of Borglum's book Sound Construction. Business materials include contracts for sculpture projects, and copyright documentation for Sound Construction. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Account Book for Sound Construction, 1923-1924; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Bank Account Books, 1903-1911, 1918; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Contracts for Sculpture Projects, 1906, 1910, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Copyright Documentation for Sound Construction, 1924; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Financial Notes, Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund, 1965-1980, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Financial Proposal, Lewis and Clark Centennial Project, circa 1905 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ledger, Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund, 1961-1998; (See Box 13, F2; not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Ledgers, 1898-1922; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 31-32)
  - Legal Documents, Solon Borglum Estate, 1922; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Price Lists, 1924, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Receipts and Statements, 1903-1972, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Ledger, Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund, 1961-1998; (See Box 8, F30; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 2)
- Printed Material, 1879-2002, undated; Series 7; (Box 9, 13-14; 1.1 linear feet)
  This series contains material on Solon Borglum's career and artwork, primarily posthumous exhibit materials and publications. Most of this material was collected by Solon's daughter Monica Borglum Davies and includes not only material on Solon, but also documents about Gutzon, Solon's assistant Paul Manship, and the Silvermine Group of Artists. Included are auction catalogs, exhibition announcements, catalogs, brochures, event programs, and informational booklets. Also found are numerous news and magazine clippings spanning over 120 years, magazines featuring large articles on Solon, newletters, press releases, reports, and other publications as well as published images of Solon and reproductions of his artwork. This series also contains copies of the art textbook Solon wrote, Sound Construction, as well as the Supplement for this work published at the same time.
  - Auction Catalogs, 1964, 1974, 1983, 1988; (partially scanned) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, 1900, 1921, 1961-1972, undated; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, School of American Sculpture, 1921-1922 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1897-1999, undated; (8 folders) (Box 9, Folder 4-11)
  - Clippings, Gutzon Borglum, 1889-1986, undated; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
  - Clippings, Silvermine Group of Artists, 1910-2002, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1879-2001, undated; (8 folders; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 16-23)
  - Essay, Phil Kovinick, "South Dakota's 'Other' Borglum", undated; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Event Programs, 1905, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Silvermine Group of Artists, 1915-1918 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition Catalog, Architectural Exhibition of the Cleveland Architectural Club, 1909 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Gutzon Borglum, 1905, 1914; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Paul Manship, 1958; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Silvermine Guild of Artists, 1910, 1946, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Solon H. Borglum, 1966-1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - German Army Songbook, 1897; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Images of Solon Borglum, undated; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Informational Booklets, undated; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Magazine, The Century, vol. 99, no. 2, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Magazine, Illustrated American, vol. 5, no. 50, 1891; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Magazine, The Kennedy Quarterly, 1962, 1965, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Magazines, Miscellaneous, 1922, 1976, 1999; (partially scanned) (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Map of Kensico Cemetery, undated; (See Box 13, F3; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Newsletters, 1972, 1974, 1982; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Newspaper, Decatur-Dekalb News, "Stone Mountain Dedication Special Edition", 1970; (See Box 13, F4; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Postcards, undated; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Press Releases, Stone Mountain Memorial Dedication, 1970; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Publication, "Celebrating the 50th Anniversary of the Silvermine Guild of Artists", 1972; (See Box 13, F5) (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Publication, Historical Biography and Libretto of the Indian Congress, 1901; (See Box 13, F6; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Publication, La Defense De Verdun, 1916; (See Box 13, F7; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Report of the American E. F. Art Training Centre, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Report of the Gordon Monument Commission, 1907; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Solon Borglum, undated; (2 folders; see also Box 13, F8; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 49-50)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Others, 1891, 1875, undated; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, 1923; (See Box 14; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, unbound version, 1923; (2 copies; see Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Supplement to Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, 1923; (See Box 14; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Supplement to Sound Construction by Solon Borglum, unbound version, 1923; (See Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1914-1974; (not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Map of Kensico Cemetery, undated; (See Box 9, F39; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 3)
  - Newspaper, Decatur-Dekalb News, "Stone Mountain Dedication Special Edition", 1970; (See Box 9, F41; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 4)
  - Publication, "Celebrating the 50th Anniversary of the Silvermine Guild of Artists", 1972; (See Box 9, F44) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 5)
  - Publication, Historical Biography and Libretto of the Indian Congress, 1901; (See Box 9, F45; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 6)
  - Publication, La Defense De Verdun, 1916; (See Box 9, F46; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 7)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Solon Borglum, undated; (See also Box 9, F49-50; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 8)
  - Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, 1923; (See Box 9, F52; not scanned) (Box 14 (sol))
  - Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, unbound version, 1923; (2 copies; see Box 9, F53) (Box 14 (sol))
  - Supplement to Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, 1923; (See Box 9, F54; not scanned) (Box 14 (sol))
  - Supplement to Sound Construction by Solon Borglum, unbound version, 1923; (See Box 9, F55) (Box 14 (sol))
- Photographs, 1864-1986; Series 8; (Box 9-13, MGP 1, MGP 3, OV 15-16; 2.0 linear feet)
  Found here are family and personal photographs, and numerous photographs of artwork by Solon Borglum. The bulk of the family and personal photographs date from Solon's adult life and include images of Solon in various settings, such as formal portraits taken throughout his career, photographs of him with his artwork, as a student and teacher in sculpture class, in Paris during his military service, with his family and friends at his farm, Rocky Ranch, and of Solon and Emma at the Crow Creek Reservation. Also found are Borglum family portraits, individual portraits of many family members including Solon's brothers Gutzon and August, and his parents James and Ida, as well as group portraits of the whole family. This subseries also includes photographs of Emma, Monica, her daughter Gwynneth, and Emma's brother Paul Vignal and his wife. Other personal photographs in this series are images of Solon at ranches and as a Boy Scout troop leader, exteriors and interiors of his various studios and residences, photos from an exhibition at the Union League Club in New York, and other miscellaneous and unidentified portraits and snapshots.
  Photographs of Artwork include files on individual works of art by Solon Borglum, as well as files for his various types of artwork, such as animal sculptures, portrait busts, and monuments and installations. Many of the files may include images of the artwork at the studio, as well as being unveiled or installed in public. Folders are arranged alphabetically by title of work, followed by categories of artwork and artwork by others. Photographs in this subseries have not been digitized.
  The Photographs series is arranged into 3 subseries. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  8.1: Family and Personal Photographs, 1864-1986, undated
  8.2: Photographs of Artwork, 1895-1967, undated
  8.3: Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, undated
  - Family and Personal Photographs, 1864-1986, undated; 8.1
    - Solon Borglum Portraits, circa 1899-1921; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 57-58)
    - Solon Borglum in Sculpture Class, 1895-1897, undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Solon Borglum with Works of Art, circa 1896-1918; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 60-61)
    - Solon Borglum in the American Expeditionary Forces, 1918-1919; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 62-63)
    - Solon Borglum at the A. E. F. School of Fine Arts, 1918-1919 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Solon Borglum's Funeral, 1922; (See Box 13, F9) (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Solon Borglum with Friends and Family, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Borglum Family Portraits, 1864, 1883-1904, undated; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
    - Solon Borglum and Family at Rocky Ranch, 1906-1929, undated; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
    - Solon Borglum and Family Dressed in Costume, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Photo Album, Solon Borglum Family, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Photo Album, Monica Borglum Davies, 1910-1920, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - August Borglum and Family, 1896, 1904, 1905, undated; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Gutzon Borglum, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Emma Borglum, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Monica Borglum Davies, circa 1904, 1986, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Gwynneth Davies Kelly, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Paul Vignal and Wife Elizabeth, circa 1890-1920, undated; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
    - Boy Scout Troop, circa 1911 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Friends of Solon Borglum, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Ranches in California and Nebraska, circa 1883-1893 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Solon Borglum Residences, 1894-1908 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Solon Borglum Studios, 1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Native American and Crow Creek Reservation, circa 1899; (2 folders; see also Box 13, F10) (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
    - B.N.L. Co. Sawmill and Dam, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Stone Mountain, undated; (See Box 13, F11; not scanned) (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Exhibition at Union League Club, New York City, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Animals, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Portraits, unidentified, undated; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 10, Folder 30-31)
    - Miscellaneous, 1864-1909, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous, unidentified, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Solon Borglum's Funeral, 1922; (See Box 9, F65) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 9)
    - Native Americans and Crow Creek Reservation, circa 1899; (See Box 10, F24-25) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 10)
    - Stone Mountain, undated; (See Box 10, F27; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1895-1967, undated; 8.2; (Not scanned)
    - "Aspiration", 1922 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "The Bells of History,", undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "The Blizzard", undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "Boy With Fish" Fountain, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "Bronchos", undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Bronchos Frightened by Saddle,", undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Bucking Broncho", 1900; (See also Box 13, F12) (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Buffalo", 1900, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "The Bull Fight", undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - "Burial on the Plains", circa 1902, undated; (See also Box 13, F13) (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "Command of God to Retreat", undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - "The Cowboy at Rest", 1903; (See also OV 15) (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - "Dancing Horse", circa 1900 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - General John B. Gordon Memorial, undated; (See also OV 15) (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Giles A. Smith Monument, undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Grant's Memorial, Model, undated (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - "The Heavens", 1915, undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - "Horse Pawing a Dead Horse", undated (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - "Indian Child Being Sent to School", undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - "The Intelligent Broncho", undated (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Jacob Leisler Monument, undated (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Joseph A. Mower Monument, undated (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - "Lassoing Wild Horses,", 1897, undated (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - "The Last Roundup", circa 1902, undated (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - "The Little Lady of the Dew" ("The Waters"), 1920, 1934, undated (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - "Monica", circa 1909, 1967, undated (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - "On the Border of Whiteman's Land", undated (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - "One in a Thousand", circa 1915 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - "Our Slave", undated (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - "Paul", undated (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - "The Pioneer", undated; (See also OV 15) (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - "The Prayer", undated (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - "Private Jones", 1960, undated (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - "Rough Rider, Bucky O'Neill Monument", circa 1906, undated; (2 folders; see also OV 15) (Box 10, Folder 67-68)
    - "Sioux Indian Buffalo Dance", undated; (See also OV 15) (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - "Snowdrift", undated; (See also OV 15) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 1)
    - "The Spirit of Death", undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 2)
    - "The Stampede of Wild Horses", 1899 (Box 11 (hol), Folder 3)
    - "Steps Toward Civilization", 1904 (Box 11 (hol), Folder 4)
    - "Tamed", undated; (See also Box 13, F14) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 5)
    - Truman J. Backus Memorial, 1909, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 6)
    - "Washington 1753", undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 7)
    - William Sody Smith Monument, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 8)
    - "Winter", circa 1898, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 9)
    - Animal Sculptures, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 10)
    - Bell Sculptures, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 11)
    - Details of Unidentified Sculptures, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 12)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 13)
    - Figure Sculptures, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 14)
    - Horse and Person Sculptures, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 15)
    - Models for Sculpture Projects, undated; (See also OV 15) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 16)
    - Monuments and Installations, 1901, 1903, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 16)
    - Paintings, 1895, 1897, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 18)
    - Portrait Busts, 1905, 1923, undated; (See also OV 15) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 19)
    - Wood Carvings, undated (Box 11 (hol), Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Sculptures, circa 1903, 1909, undated; (See also Box 13, F15 and OV 16) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 21)
    - Photo Albums of Artwork, circa 1899, undated; (7 folders) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 22-28)
    - Solon H. Borglum Memorial Window by D. Putnam Brinley, circa 1922 (Box 11 (hol), Folder 29)
    - Artwork by Gutzon Borglum, 1904, 1907, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 1)
    - Artwork by Others, 1898, 1919, 1923, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 2)
    - "Bucking Broncho", 1900; (See also Box 10, F40) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 12)
    - "Burial on the Plains", circa 1902, undated; (See also Box 10, F43) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 13)
    - "Tamed", undated; (See also Box 11, F5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Sculptures, 1909, undated; (See also Box 11, F21) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 15)
    - "The Cowboy at Rest", 1903; (See also Box 10, F45) (Box OV 15)
    - General John B. Gordon Memorial, undated; (See also Box 10, F47) (Box OV 15)
    - "The Pioneer", undated; (See also Box 10, F64) (Box OV 15)
    - "Rough Rider, Bucky O'Neill Monument", circa 1906, undated; (See also Box 10, F67-68) (Box OV 15)
    - "Sioux Indian Buffalo Dance", undated; (See also Box 10, F69) (Box OV 15)
    - "Snowdrift", undated; (See also Box 11, F1) (Box OV 15)
    - Models for Sculpture Projects, undated; (See also Box 11, F16) (Box OV 15)